Matthew Suttie

Github: github.com/ChronoLogic12 Website: matthewsuttie.com email: msuttie12@hotmail.com

Mobile: 07908147256

Junior Web Developer

I am a web developer and have recently completed a level 5 NVQ in web development with Code Institute. After independently studying coding through Codecademy and finding it engaging and fulfilling I have committed to pursuing web development as a career. I have since completed several projects, both front end and full stack, gaining a broad knowledge of coding languages and frameworks. With proficiency in Adobe Photoshop and Adobe XD and almost eight years of experience in specialised, customer facing roles, I am excited to apply myself toward a new opportunity.

Technical Skill Set

Technologies

- JavaScript
- HTML5
- CSS3
- Python

Databases

- MongoDB
- MySQL

Frameworks / Libraries

- Django
- Flask
- jQuery
- Materialize
- Bootstrap
- Stripe

Version Control/Hosting

- Git
- Github
- Heroku
- Netlify
- Cloudinary
- AWS S3

Portfolio Projects

For a full list of previous projects including links to live and demo sites as well as their code repositories please see my portfolio site.

Professional Experience

Greenlawns Kennels (live site)

Web & Graphic Designer

2020

I worked in a two person team to design and develop a website for a local business.

Key responsibilities

- Creating both low and high fidelity wireframes.
- Designing page layouts, UX and colour schemes using Adobe XD.
- Creating all custom graphics using Adobe Photoshop and sourcing 3rd party icons and images.
- Editing images provided by the client for use within the site.
- Working closely with the lead developer throughout the full development process.

Waitrose & Partners

2015 – 2021

Fruit, Vegetable and Horticulture Specialist

I worked as a specialist promoting and managing fresh produce and training partners (employees) to meet company standards.

Key responsibilities

- Engaging and advising customers to enhance their shopping experience.
- Driving and improving sales through the application of specialist product and service knowledge.
- Improving personal and team knowledge through partner training and development of documentation.
- Implementing stock management techniques to reduce waste and increase profitability.

Ceritech Audio 2013 – 2015

AV Sales Consultant

In this role I developed an expansive product knowledge of high end Hi-Fi and home cinema to design and sell custom audiovisual solutions.

Key responsibilities

- Creating bespoke audiovisual solutions to satisfy customer specifications.
- Demonstration, Installation and configuration of digital systems.
- Collaborating with expert team members to ensure customers receive their desired outcomes.
- Meeting and learning from suppliers to expand product and industry knowledge.

Education & Training

Education:

2021-2022 Code institute - Level 5 NVQ - Diploma in Web App Development

2018-2019 Waitrose - Internal qualification - Fruit, Vegetable and Horticulture Specialist

2015 Ceritech Audio - Level 2 NVQ - Customer service

A Levels Music Technology, Music, Physics, Biology

GCSE 11 of grade C or above including Maths and English

Technical Courses Completed:

2019+ Codecademy Javascript, C#, CSS, SCSS, RegEx and others.

Interests & Additional information

- I participated in the Code Institute Pride Hackathon; Our project 'Light Up' won 2nd place!
- I am a passionate musician and play the flute (grade 7) and guitar to a high standard as well as several other instruments.
- I am an avid climber and particularly enjoy the combination of problem solving with both strength and flexibility training.
- I enjoy reading, especially sci-fi and fantasy works.
- I hold a full UK Drivers License.

References are available upon request.